<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.wordhunter.app</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>AGPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>Word Hunter</name>
  <summary>Local-first reader and vocabulary trainer</summary>
  <developer id="com.wordhunter">
    <name>Word Hunter</name>
  </developer>
  <icon type="stock">com.wordhunter.app</icon>
  <description>
    <p>
      Word Hunter is a desktop language-learning workspace for reading real
      texts, saving vocabulary with context, and reviewing words later.
    </p>
    <p>
      It supports imported text, PDFs, EPUB files, subtitles, public-domain
      book discovery, local vocabulary storage, spaced repetition, text to
      speech, and optional offline translation models.
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.wordhunter.app.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://ironship.github.io/WordHunter-site/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/Ironship/WordHunter/issues</url>
  <categories>
    <category>Education</category>
    <category>Languages</category>
  </categories>
  <provides>
    <binary>word-hunter-rustified</binary>
  </provides>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Ironship/WordHunter/main/docs/screenshots/pc-reader.png</image>
      <caption>Reading view with vocabulary highlights and word details</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.0.5" date="2026-07-16">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Add 48 original A1-B2 graded readers across 12 learning languages.</li>
          <li>Let readers choose and reorder selected-word controls and save grammatical articles.</li>
          <li>Improve Pocket word panels, flashcards, progress charts, themes, accessibility, and desktop layouts.</li>
          <li>Fix Reader refreshes, stale synchronization updates, review races, selection return, and delayed translations.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.5~rc.10" date="2026-07-16" type="development">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Replace course-style claims with 48 original A1-B2 graded readers across all 12 named learning languages.</li>
          <li>Provide continuous, progressively leveled stories for reading comprehension and contextual vocabulary.</li>
          <li>Correct reader titles and cover metadata throughout the built-in Library catalog.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.5~rc.9" date="2026-07-15" type="development">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Add 48 original A1-B2 books across all 12 named learning languages.</li>
          <li>Offer lessons, dialogues, practical texts, contextual vocabulary, and practice activities.</li>
          <li>Use CEFR-inspired levels for Latin and Ancient Greek.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.5~rc.8" date="2026-07-15" type="development">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Keep the Pocket word sheet at a stable usable height in expanded, collapsed, and custom positions.</li>
          <li>Let the grammatical Article field be shown, hidden, and reordered with the other selected-word items.</li>
          <li>Collapse the long word-panel ordering controls in Reader settings when they are not needed.</li>
          <li>Keep background synchronization from rebuilding an unchanged Reader and returning it to the top.</li>
          <li>Restore complete frontend release validation after the RC7 TypeScript additions.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.5~rc.7" date="2026-07-15" type="development">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Let the Pocket word card travel across most of the screen and keep its chosen height when Smart Suggestion changes.</li>
          <li>Make word-card swipes easier and move larger navigation targets closer to the bottom of tall phones.</li>
          <li>Add visible grammatical-article editing, suggestions, display, flashcards, search, and import/export support.</li>
          <li>Recognize French and Italian apostrophe articles without creating duplicate vocabulary keys.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.5~rc.6" date="2026-07-14" type="development">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Prevent stale synchronization snapshots from reverting newly changed word statuses.</li>
          <li>Acknowledge backend snapshots only after the frontend accepts the exact revision.</li>
          <li>Return Ctrl+Enter to the selected Reader word without falling back to the page start.</li>
          <li>Keep delayed SRS grades from overwriting newer status changes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.5~rc.5" date="2026-07-14" type="development">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Extend the Pocket word-sheet drag range and retain intermediate heights between cards.</li>
          <li>Tint the complete selected-word card to match New, Learning, Known, or Ignored status.</li>
          <li>Keep status controls, outgoing card colors, and loading states synchronized.</li>
          <li>Avoid rebuilding release artifacts after a validated draft is published.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.5~rc.4" date="2026-07-14" type="development">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Run complete word selection and automatic translation after Reader swipes.</li>
          <li>Add a draggable collapsed or expanded Pocket word-panel sheet with an accessible handle.</li>
          <li>Animate horizontal card drags with immediate content updates and layered transitions.</li>
          <li>Prevent stale translation refreshes and improve gesture release handling.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.5~rc.3" date="2026-07-14" type="development">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Keep Familiar desktop themes dark from the first paint and in embedded tools.</li>
          <li>Add swipe navigation with directional animation to selected Reader words.</li>
          <li>Turn Flashcards into a card-first deck with tap-to-reveal and safe swipe navigation.</li>
          <li>Open clipped Pocket heatmaps at the latest weeks in Graphs and Flashcards.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.5~rc.2" date="2026-07-13" type="development">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Give each light desktop theme a distinct background and panel surface instead of plain white.</li>
          <li>Fix the desktop Edit Book dialog so labels stay compact and fields use the available width.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.5~rc.1" date="2026-07-13" type="development">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Test prerelease: migrate the browser runtime to TypeScript with a deterministic generated frontend.</li>
          <li>Add configurable visibility and ordering for selected-word panel sections and actions.</li>
          <li>Move Pocket word actions higher and improve theme, state, dialog, and drawer reliability.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.4" date="2026-07-12">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed Windows saves and startup recovery failing with access denied while synchronizing backup files.</li>
          <li>Made Pocket clearly explain when a scanned PDF requires desktop OCR before synchronization.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.3" date="2026-07-11">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed the Android Import drawer closing whenever a user tapped one of its controls.</li>
          <li>Included the OCR reliability, progress animation, synchronized counters, and sentence correction fixes from the withdrawn 1.0.1 and 1.0.2 builds.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.2" date="2026-07-11">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Restored the live PaddleOCR progress animation with a clearer document-scanning indicator.</li>
          <li>Changed quick PDF sentence correction to edit and replace only the selected sentence.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.1" date="2026-07-11">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added automatic CPU recovery when accelerated PDF OCR fails at runtime.</li>
          <li>Kept library word counters stable while synchronized book text refreshes in the background.</li>
          <li>Updated release workflows to supported GitHub Actions runtimes and corrected Rust toolchain setup.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-07-10">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Established a new compatibility baseline after breaking storage and synchronization changes.</li>
          <li>Added durable per-record local storage, safer recovery, and deterministic cross-device conflict handling.</li>
          <li>Added guided Syncthing setup on desktop and staged folder synchronization on Android.</li>
          <li>Refreshed Windows, Android, and x86_64 Flatpak packaging, validation, and third-party license notices.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.6.2" date="2026-07-03">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added a managed cloud sync coordinator with a Flatpak Google Drive connector through bundled rclone; cloud pulls are staged and validated before merge, and the MVP does not delete remote files.</li>
          <li>Recovered interrupted Google Drive authorization by clearing partial app-owned rclone remotes and showing a retryable sign-in state.</li>
          <li>Retried transient Google Drive quota and rate-limit failures while preparing the cloud sync folder.</li>
          <li>Kept the visible Google Drive connector status stable across local/background sync snapshots instead of falling back to not connected after a successful connection.</li>
          <li>Removed the separate Discover language selector; book discovery now follows the active learning profile language on desktop and Android.</li>
          <li>Fixed Discover source selection so switching to Wikipedia, Wikinews, or Wikisource is preserved across Flatpak/background sync snapshots.</li>
          <li>Improved the Linux/Flatpak GTK titlebar workaround so close and maximize buttons keep receiving clicks in normal window mode.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.6.1" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed Flatpak sync folder selection so the chosen folder is stored only after a successful sync and uses XDG config/data locations.</li>
          <li>Fixed Flatpak/Linux OCR GPU platform detection for more reliable startup diagnostics.</li>
          <li>Bundled WebGPU/Vulkan OCR acceleration with a safe CPU fallback, PDFium, and PaddleOCR models for scanned PDFs on Linux.</li>
          <li>Refreshed Windows packaging so installer and portable builds include the required GNU runtime DLLs.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.6" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added Linux Flatpak packaging with AppStream metadata and local install helpers.</li>
          <li>Improved PDF reading with page-background overlays, selectable words, and a clean text mode.</li>
          <li>Improved Android Pocket PDF rendering with zooming, horizontal panning, and text-layer spacing fixes.</li>
          <li>Hardened local-first storage, backup, recovery, and sync compatibility paths.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
</component>
