<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.wordhunter.app</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>AGPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>Word Hunter</name>
  <summary>Local-first reader and vocabulary trainer</summary>
  <developer id="com.wordhunter">
    <name>Word Hunter</name>
  </developer>
  <icon type="stock">com.wordhunter.app</icon>
  <description>
    <p>
      Word Hunter is a language-learning workspace for reading real texts,
      saving vocabulary with context, and reviewing words later.
    </p>
    <p>
      It supports imported text, PDFs, EPUB files, subtitles, local vocabulary
      storage, spaced repetition, text to speech, and optional offline
      translation models.
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">Word Hunter.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://ironship.github.io/WordHunter-site/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/Ironship/WordHunter/issues</url>
  <categories>
    <category>Education</category>
    <category>Languages</category>
  </categories>
  <provides>
    <binary>word-hunter-rustified</binary>
  </provides>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Ironship/WordHunter/main/docs/screenshots/pc-reader.png</image>
      <caption>Reading view with vocabulary highlights and word details</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.0.8" date="2026-07-23">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Make later vocabulary status decisions win reliably across synchronized devices.</li>
          <li>Merge notes and translations without restoring stale word statuses.</li>
          <li>Reduce Android startup work and bundle the initial JavaScript graph.</li>
          <li>Restrict Android cleartext networking to the local Word Hunter backend.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.7.1" date="2026-07-20">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix flashcard word and sentence speech so it follows the visible card.</li>
          <li>Keep the desktop Word Panel synchronized with keyboard navigation.</li>
          <li>Restore spoken-word highlighting for Edge TTS on Windows.</li>
          <li>Add and document desktop Reader keyboard shortcuts.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.7" date="2026-07-20">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Add exact-word Reader bookmarks and restore the last reading position.</li>
          <li>Harden synchronization, backups, imports, and custom-book persistence.</li>
          <li>Improve Android synchronization, text-to-speech controls, and conflict resolution.</li>
          <li>Add validated Apple Silicon, AppImage, DEB, Snap, AUR, and Nix packaging paths.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.6" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Keep Reader playback anchored to the selected word.</li>
          <li>Delay the first in-text review of newly learned words until the following day.</li>
          <li>Correct Italian interface copy and built-in reader titles.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
</component>
